## MOHD FARHAN BIN NAZMI 013-3112762

farhannazmi90@gmail.com

PT 2650, Taman Desa Kemumin, Jalan Pengkalan Chepa, Kota Bharu, 16100, KELANTAN DARUL NAIM

#### **SUMMARY**

With almost two years working experiences as Mechanical Engineer with strong technical background in process mechanical, system and quality process, I am currently in search of career enhancement and ready to challenge myself with new opportunities offered by your respected organization and looking forward to bring my knowledge, experiences and skills to the best level at your organization. Currently expose with new working environment in process engineering in order to develop more skills and experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor's Degree** 

Field of Study : Engineering

Major : Bachelor (Hons) of Mechanical Manufacturing Engineering

Institute/University : International Islamic University Malaysia (IIUM

: (SECOND CLASS (UPPER) HONOURS)

Higher Secondary/STPM/"A" Level/Pre-U

Field of Study : Pre-Engineering
Major : Engineering

Institute/University : Centre of Foundation of International Islamic University

Malaysia

Professional Certificate in AutoCAD 2013 Pro (2014)



الجامعة الاسلامية العالمية مالبنيا

وني كرسيتي استارا رانتازا بغيما ملكست

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

# SAMSUNG SDI ENERGY MALAYSIA SDN BHD, SENAWANG, NEGERI SEMBILAN



## (December 2014 to present)

Samsung SDIEM is a secondary battery manufacturer, specifically Lithium Ion Batteries, to meet customer requirement for various applications such as smartphones, laptop and other electronic devices.

#### Position:

### Process Engineer (ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT) (December 2014 – present)

Assembly Group, Cylindrical Process Engineering Department – Responsible for evaluating existing cylindrical battery type manufacturing processes and configuring manufacturing system to reduce defect, cost, improve sustainability and develop best practices within the production process.

#### **Job Description**

- Evaluate and improve on processes in manufacturing system, especially in reducing defect
- Maintain reliable and safe manufacturing systems while improving production rates, efficiencies, yields, costs and changeovers
- Improve process capability and production volume while maintaining and improving quality standards
- Prepare samples for analysis
- > Develop and implement systems that optimize all phases of production process.
- Advise on corrective actions related to engineering side.
- Work with production members to ensure maintaining the product quality and improving the production

#### Training Attended

☐ 7 Quality Control Tools Training, Process Management Knowledge for Engineer and Production, UBAH @ Work Training, Microsoft Excel



### PERSONAL PROFILE

**Age** : 26

I/C No : 900322-03-6211

Marital Status: SingleReligion: IslamRace: MalayNationality: MalaysianHealth: Excellent

## LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

	MALAY	ENGLISH
Reading	10	10
Speaking & Writing	10	8

### **PERSONALITY**

- Self-motivated
- Can accept criticism and advice in order to increase the quality of job and performance
- A creative person in creating new idea and solving problems
- Willing to learn new things
- Have leadership skills and ability to work in team
- Responsibility in doing all jobs that was giving to me
- Experience in leading a team in course work and extra curriculum activities
- Capable event manager in handling small scale event

### **JOB PREFERENCES**

**Availability**: After one month

notice

Willing to travel : Yes
Willing to travel : Yes
Have own transport : Yes
Expected Salary : RM3500

#### **ENGINEERING INDUSTRIAL TRAINING:**

(June 2013 – September 2013)

MSET Shipbuilding Corporation Sdn. Bhd, Kuala Terengganu, Terengganu.



#### Responsibilities

- Assisted the workers in making the parts that are needed to be repaired on the ship.
- Giving ideas to the workers to make new parts in the ship.
- Ensure that all of the repairing processes are based on schedule.
- Make sure that all of the raw materials (aluminum, marine steel) are delivered in time.
- Assisted the workers to solve the new problem arise.

#### **Achievements**

- Handling various manufacturing machine (e.g. CNC Milling, CNC Turning, polishing, grinding and milling)
- Check and learned on how to deal with other company to buy spare parts.

# AUTOMOTIVE INDUSTRY CERTIFICATION ENGINEERING (AICE) PROGRAMME:



Malaysia Automotive Institute (MAI) (June 2014 - August 2014)

## **Description:**

The objectives of AICE program are to train fresh engineering graduates to become competent engineers that are immediate recruit (employable) to the industry and the same time create employment opportunities for AICE participants in industry.

### **COURSE HIGHLIGHTS**

- 1. Production Planning and Control
- 2. Product Design and Development
- 3. Computer Integrated Manufacturing (Cim)
- 4. Engineering Management
- 5. Production Tooling
- 6. Programming for Engineers
- 7. Static, Dynamic and Thermo fluid
- 8. Manufacturing Automation
- 9. Engineering Ethics Safety and Environment
- 10. Quality Control
- 11. Computer Aided Design and Manufacturing(Cad/Cam)
- 12. Mechanics of Material

### **OTHER CREDENTIALS**

Skill	Duration	Proficiency
MS Office	>5 years	Intermediate
Advanced and Accumulated Quality Management System	>1 years	Intermediate
Quality Management System	>1 years	Intermediate
Minitab	>1 years	Intermediate
TIBCO Spotfire	>1 years	Intermediate
Alibre Design	>1 years	Intermediate
Catia P3 V5R19	>1 years	Intermediate
Manufacturing Execution System	>1 years	Intermediate
AutoCad	>5 month	Intermediate

#### REFERENCES

Name : Mr. Muhammad

Ashraf bin Othman

Position : Senior Engineer Company : Samsung SDIEM

Telephone : 013-2036155

Name : Mr. Wan Mohd Hanif

Bin Wan Ismail

Position : Senior Engineer Company : Samsung SDIEM

Telephone : 014-5417226